Well, it's about time.
I knew that if I tormented
these children long enough,
you'd emerge from your
musty hole sooner or later.
Hmph.
Time has been kind to you.
If I didn't know better, you
could almost pass for human.
My, my, how cavalier you've become.
You were nothing like this the
last time I saw you, little one.
You were so timid.
Why, when you stood before
me two centuries ago,
your teeth couldn't stop chattering.
Remember, Lycerus?
Do not call me by that name, Quinella.
My name is Cardinal.
I am a program with one
directive, deleting you.
That's right, you are.
However, my name is Administrator, and
my directive is to manage all programs.
I'm sorry it took so long
for us to meet again?
But you see, I was preparing
a special art to welcome you!
and finishing it took
longer than expected.
Damn you!
You cut the address loose!
I came so close to killing you 200 years
ago, but I let you slip through my fingers?
and I wanted to make sure
that didn't happen again.
So, I learned from my mistake
and came up with a plan.
All I had to do was lure you out again
and trap you on this side, with me.
Like a mouse in the same cage with a cat.
At this point, it is not clear who
is the mouse and who is the cat.
You are trapped in here as well.
And as you can plainly see, there
are four of us, and only one of you.
Four against one, you say?
Hardly.
Your numbers are off by a
wide margin, little one.
What?
In fact, and this does not
include myself, mind you,
it's four against three hundred.
Three hundred? What?
You vile monster, is there
no limit to your depravity?
Your duty is to protect your
subjects and you turn them into that?
Wait, subjects?
That thing?
Then, that monster at
its core, this human?
You say such silly things about trifles
such as duties and subjects to protect.
I am a conqueror.
I have no problem as
long as whatever I rule
over remains subservient
and obeys my will.
Whether they be sword or
human matters not to me.
You horrid! Oh,
now don't tell me you're
shocked that I used a
little thing like matter
conversion on human units.
It was only a measly 300 or so.
You are evil.
This one is just a prototype, by the way.
In order to mass-produce the final version
in sufficient numbers
to handle the load test,
I expect I will need...
oh, about half. Half? Of what?
Why, naturally, of the 80,000 human
units living in the Human Empire.
Yes, that amount should
be enough, I think.
To repel the armies of the Dark Territory
and take the fight back to their side.
Well I hope that allays
your fears, little Alice.
Your precious human empire will be
more than protected, Madam Pontifex.
It is clear my words cannot reach you now.
Therefore, as a fellow sacred arts user,
I would like to know
where the owners are of
the 30 swords you
fashioned that monstrosity?
out of.
Even if you flouted the rule allowing
perfect control over one weapon,
Pontifex or no, you cannot
break the next rule.
To activate memory release,
there must be a bond
between the weapon and its owner.
Pontifex,
if you truly used innocent humans as the
source of the blades
which make up that thing,
there is no way they
would form a bond with
you!
The explanation is hiding
in plain sight, my dear.
Eugeo seems to have already discovered it.
No!
What?
See the crystals on the ceiling?
They're not decorations.
They're what she stole from the
Knights with the Synthesis Ritual.
Those are their memories!
Curse you, Queen Ella!
You fiend!
Toying like this with the
humans is beyond twisted!
You placed the memory fragments you stole
into mental models on fresh light cubes.
That is all it would take to
create simulated human beings.
But their intelligence
would be severely limited,
and they would not be able to
execute an advanced command?
such as perfect weapon control.
But you can get around that
if the memory fragment and
the weapon it is linked to
share the same structural data.
The memories of people the
knights once held dear.
The memories you stole and
carved onto these crystals.
They are what your golem is made of.
Isn't that right?
These artificial personas
desire but one thing.
To find the one they remember,
touch them, hold them, possess them.
Unseemly desire courses throughout this
puppet and provides its motivation.
They sense the ones they remember
are near, but they cannot touch them.
They cannot be one with them.
Their thirst for that connection
drives them to the point of madness.
But all they can see now are the
enemies standing in their way.
They think if they can destroy you,
the one they desire will become theirs.
That is why they fight.
And no matter how badly they're
wounded, or how many times they fall,
they'll keep fighting for eternity.
I designed it rather well, did I not?
The power of desire can achieve
great things if harnessed properly.
You're wrong!
Don't you dare tarnish that
emotion by calling it desire!
What they feel is...
is pure love!
Well, now you're just
splitting hairs, little one.
Love is control.
Love is desire.
Either way, it is a signal produced
by a Fluctlight, nothing more.
Which brings us to an
even greater revelation.
Now that you know the truth about my
fearsome puppet, you cannot destroy it.
Because every single
blade is a living human
being who has been
transformed into a sword.
Yes, you're right.
I cannot kill a human.
I spent the past 200 years owning an
art to kill you and your inhuman form,
but it was all for nothing.
You are such a fool!
It's both funny and tragic.
You knew that all life
in this world was just
a collection of data
that can be rewritten,
and yet you treat it as human.
I did, because they are human.
The people of the Underworld have the
emotions you and I lost, Quinella.
They can laugh, grieve,
feel joy, and love.
That is what makes them human.
I will let you take my life!
But first, I want your word that
you will spare these young ones!
No, you can't!
Out of curiosity, let us
say I accepted your offer.
What would I stand to gain from it?
If you decide to fight, I will not
only keep your pathetic puppet at bay,
I will shave off at least
half of your life as well.
The loss of that would put an even greater
strain on your already
dwindling memory capacity,
would it not?
Hmm.
Very well, then.
Letting them go now gives me
something to look forward to later.
All right, I swear on the goddess
Stacia, after I kill - No, not on a god.
You'll swear on the one
thing you value most.
Your Fluctlight, or the deal is off.
Fine, fine.
I hereby swear on my
Fluctlight and all the
precious data I've accumulated up to now.
After I've killed you, little one, I shall
allow those three to escape unharmed.
You had better.
I am sorry.
Oh.
Was that your best?
Fire all you want, I...
I'm holding back for now, little one.
After all, what fun would it
be if I dispatched you quickly?
I have been waiting 200
years for this moment!
I can't!
Stay back!
What's that?
I can't help.
All I can do is stand here. Powerless.
Thank.
There has to be something I can do.
Instead of whining about being
weak, find a way to fight back.
Now, to finish our centuries-long game.
Farewell, dear Lycerin.
Farewell, my only daughter.
Farewell, my other self!
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
No need to apologize.
You still have a mission
to fulfill, don't you?
The three of you will save this
world fragile and beautiful.
We will, no matter what.
You have given me a second chance.
And I shall use it to defend this world.
You two!
That's it.
I finally figured it out.
I know what my purpose is supposed to be.
I'm not going to run away.
I'm going to stay and fulfill my duty.
Please, Cardinal.
With whatever strength you have left,
I want you to turn me into a sword.
Just like her puppet.
Yuji-ho, you can't...
Even if she lets us go, Administrator will
still change half the people into golems.
We can't let her do that to them.
If there's any chance left to stop her,
any hope left at all, this
sacred art must be it.
System call.
Remove core protection.
Go ahead now.
Change me.
The bond between us is strong.
Much stronger than her and
that monster's. Stop it.
Don't do this.
It's okay.
This is what I was meant to do.
Very well, Ugeo.
The final art I cast in life
will go toward your objective.
Hold on.
Before I go, I need to
tell you one last thing.
Metal weapons don't work on the Pontifex,
that's why I couldn't
stab her with my dagger.
Now what?
What do you think you're doing?
Would you die already? No, you don't!
Your lightning will not work on me!
You insolent little knight!
How dare you defy me!
I shall burn all three of you to cinders!
And I shall stop you again!
Release, recollection.
You can mimic my spell, fool.
However, one paltry sword is no match
against my Golem of Thirty Blades!
It will snap it in half
with a single blow!
Human love, beautiful,
the shining light of
purpose, so beautiful.
Yeah, it is.
Kirito, I must go now.
Protect this world and its people.
I leave it to you.
Pucho.
Well, well.
You want to fight some more, little boy?
Do not make the mistake
of becoming overconfident
just because you demolished my puppet.
Don't do it.
Don't go.
Yu-Gi-Oh!
Richard Craig!
Oh, my God.
I did not see that coming.
In terms of priority level,
the sword that fused with Eugeo was no
match for my blade, the Silvery Eternity.
But I did not realize his
sword was not metallic.
That was my mistake.
What a bother.
So, it seems you are
the last one standing.
Surprising, to say the least,
boy from the other side.
I am still curious as to why you're
here without administrator privileges.
Although at this point, it doesn't matter.
Now the fight is over, I'm sleepy.
I'll ask the other boy from the
outer world why you were here,
after I fill my chamber
with your blood and screams.
This is the end, boy.
Perhaps we will meet again
someday on the other side.
It's happening again.
I'm letting it happen again.
You do not have to win all the time!
And if you lose, what does it even matter?
In the end, what does is that your
heart and will are remembered.
I am certain everyone
who has spent time with
you and moved on to other
planes believed that,
as do I.
We have given you the strength to stand.
So stand and protect those you hold dear.
Well, now, you can move, can't you?
Yeah, I can take it from here.
If you wish, have had it.
You fought hard, Alice.
And now it's my turn.
Charlotte, Cardinal, and Jujo.
They gave their lives for mine.
Now I'll give mine for yours.
Love you.
Don't try to meet you.
It's the kind of the moment.
You can see the bright blue light.
You can see the truth.
You can't see the voice of the voice.
Don't let anyone know who won't be.
You can't see the rule.
Thank
you
so
much for watching.
Next time, my hero?